James McCarthy

7 Eastcote Drive Harpenden, Herts AL5 1SE 07437 323746 jamesmccarthy150@gmail.com

SKILLS

I am an energetic, hard working and resilient team member. I'm also a very confident and enthusiastic worker, with a passion for helping others, and making sure their needs are met. I enjoy giving others the best experience they can, and providing them with the best product they can.

EXPERIENCE

Student Technical Director - Sir John Lawes

2017 - PRESENT

• I am the Student Technical Director of my school's events, running the lighting and sound elements of all of the shows, put on by the school, or using the school's equipment.

Scouting Young Leader - 10th Harpenden Swift Pack

April 2014 - PRESENT

 I assist the Adult Leaders in organising, and running the Cub evenings and camps to allow the children to make the most of their time, and supporting the local community.

Explorers Committee - Harpenden Explorer Scout Unit (HESU)

2018 - PRESENT

• I am on the team that runs the Explorer Scout meetings every week.

Harpenden Gangshow - Cast Member

September 2014 - PRESENT

• I am a member of the Cast that puts on the Harpenden Gangshow - An ametur production which fundraises for the Scouting District, all put on by volunteers.

EDUCATION

Sir John Lawes School, Harpenden - Currently doing GCSEs

September 2015 - July 2020

Currently Taking:

English, Maths, Biology, Chemistry, Physics, Computer Science, Design & Technology, Geography and Media GCSEs (Predicted Average Point Score: 7.29 (Half way between an A and A*))

A Levels:

I am planning to take 3 A Levels at Sir John Lawes.

These are: Physics, Maths and Computer Science.

AWARDS

- 10th Harpenden Scouts Cliff Brotherton Award (2017):
 - I won the award as I was the scout that made the biggest and best impact to the troop and scouting community over that year.
- Key Stage 3 Computer Science Award:
 - I won the academic award out of Years 7, 8 and 9 because I produced the best computer science work while in Year 8, as well as showed a real aptitude for the subject.
- Key Stage 3 Media Award:
 - I won the Media Award, as I ran my school's half-termly news report the Newscast almost single handedly, for almost a year, while in Year 9.
- GCSE Product Design Award:
 - I won the Product Design Award as I was the student that produced the best work through the course of Year 10, in the various projects and products I made.
- Duke Of Edinburgh Bronze Award:
 - I achieved my Duke Of Edinburgh Bronze Award, through a combination of my Gang Show, Newscast, Young Leaders at Cubs, and a final Expedition, where I lead my group across the countryside.